(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T21:03:05.472902",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あなたのアイドル
Your idol
サインはB
Sign is B
チュッ！
Chu!
ようやく会えたね 嬉しいね
We finally met, I'm so happy
待ち遠しくて 足をバタバタさせながら
Waiting anxiously, kicking my feet,
今日楽しみで 眠れなかったよ
Couldn't sleep because I was excited,
寝れなかったよ
Couldn't sleep at all.
（おれも～！）
(Me too!)
緊張なんかしてる場合じゃない
This is no time to be nervous,
一分一秒無駄になってできない
We can't waste a single minute or second.
さあ 始めましょう
Now, let's begin.
きみも きみも きみも お待ちどうさま
You, you, you, thank you for waiting.
手を鳴らせ いらっしゃいませ
Clap your hands, welcome.
スキが集まる場所へようこそ！
Welcome to where love gathers!
日常は苦悩苦の中
Daily life is filled with agony.
ここに来たなら 踊らなきゃ損損損
If you're here, you've got to dance!
人がいようが 今関係ない
It doesn't matter if people are watching.
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
Don't worry about the size of the box.
ちゃんと見えてる きみのサイリウム
I can see your penlight clearly.
いまは ふっと吹けば飛ぶような 小さな小さな才能だけど
Right now, like a tiny talent ready to fly away,
私を押してくれるのなら
If you're going to support me,
バクレツを上げる
I'll give you an explosion of popularity!
あなたのアイドル
Your idol
サインはB
Sign is B
チュッ！
Chu!
あいつは俺が育てたって
"I raised that guy,"
近い将来自慢してほしいよ
I want you to brag about it soon.
こうしちゃいられない
We can't just stay like this.
きみと！きみと！いまを楽しまなきゃ
With you! Now we've got to have fun!
引きこもりの ヒキニシりも
Hikikomori and shy people too,
普段と違う顔見せてよ
Show me a different face than usual.
みんな兄弟 調子どうだい
Everyone is a sibling, how's it going?
なりふり構わずにさあさあさあ
Without caring about appearances, go!
人に笑われていても関係ない
It doesn't matter if people laugh at you.
周りがどうとかこうとか気にしない
Don't worry about what others say.
主張強すぎ きみのサイリウム
Your penlight is too strong-willed.
たとえ世界がわたしを拒んで ひとりぼっちを感じたとしても
Even if the world rejects me and I feel all alone,
あなたが味方でいてくれたら 怖いものはないよ
If you are on my side, there's nothing to be afraid of.
あなたのアイドル
Your idol
サインはB
Sign is B
チュッ！
Chu!
みてよ みてよ
Look, look,
なにか始まる きみとの物語が
Something is starting, a story with you.
ああ なんて素晴らしい景色だ！
Ah, what a wonderful scenery!
びっことかみまいとか関係ない
It doesn't matter if you're big or small.
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
Don't worry about the size of the box.
ちゃんと見えてる きみの
I can see your penlight clearly...
あなたのアイドル サインはB！
We are your idols, our sign is B!
ちゅっ
Chu!
(B小町！ふふー！)
(B-Komachi! Hufu!)
ようやく会えたね 嬉しいね
I'm so happy that we finally met,
待ち遠しくって 足をバタバタさせながら
my legs were trembling while waiting impatiently.
今日楽しみで 眠れなかったよ
I couldn't sleep because I was so excited for today.
(俺もー！)
(Me too!)
緊張なんてしてる場合じゃない
It's not the time to be nervous,
一分一秒 無駄になんてできない
I can't waste a single minute or second.
さあ 始めましょう
So let's begin!
君も！君も！君も！
You too! You too! You too!
(はあい！はあい！)
(Hai! Hai!)
お待ちどうさま
Can't wait!
(はい！はい！はい！はい！)
(Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!)
手を鳴らし いらっしゃいませ
Clap your hands together, welcome!
“好き”が集まる場所へ ようこそ
Welcome to the place where fondness gathers,
(ふわ！ふわ！)
(Fuwa! Fuwa!)
日常は黒幕の中
everyday life is in the cloakroom.
ここに来たんだ 踊らにゃ 損！損！損！
If you've come here, if you don't dance it's a loss! Loss! Loss!
人がいようがまいが 関係ない
Whether or not people are here, it's irrelevant.
箱が大きい小さいとか 気にしない
We don't care if the venue is big or small.
ちゃんと見えてる 君のサイリウム
We can see your glow sticks well.
今は ふうっと吹けば飛ぶような
Now, if we blow with a puff, it's like it'll fly though,
小さな小さな才能だけど
it's just a tiny little talent.
私を押してくれるのなら
As long as you support me,
バクレすをあげる
I'll give you a huge response.
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall,
今日はボロレル
today is a bolero.
騒げいた少年 甘酸っぱいレモン
Melted boy, bittersweet lemon,
求人人類♥満杯 オープントースターは漏れ漏れよ
craving humanity, full of pies, the toaster is leaking, leaking!
おかわりはアンコール次第ね
Seconds depend on the encore.
終わらないラブコール・ノ・ダンス・デ
In an endless love call dance,
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
おかわりならもう欲しい
If you want seconds, I already want them.
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
終わらないラブコール・ノ・ダンス・デ
In an endless love call dance,
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
おかわりならもう欲しい
If you want seconds, I already want them.
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
3.1415926535のπだって 割り切れない気持ち抱えてるよ
Even pi, 3.1415926535, carries an un-divisible feeling.
ロボ人も原人もエンジンもエンジン組んで仲良くやれたらとか
Robo-humans, cavemen, and engines coupling, if only we could get along...
割れない命 いそがいのヘブン 今宵はいいんじゃない？
Undeletable life is a busy heaven, isn't it nice tonight?
ほらおえおえおえおえよ
Hey, oeo eoeo yo!
踊ればいいんじゃない？
Wouldn't it be nice to dance?
ほらふりふりふりふれば 休戦しようぜ
Hey, if you swing and shake, let's call a truce!
涙腺が源泉温泉 汗ぱんだららんさんさんさいったんだ
Tear ducts are hot spring sources, sweating, rattling, what are you saying?
高まった感動の再会
Reunited with heightened emotion,
集まった愛情のwi-fi
gathered Wi-Fi of affection,
持ち寄った上通りのneon light
brought together fine neon lights.
愛してるが重たすぎて 狂い立った人類の状態
"I love you" overlaps, twisted state of humanity,
熱いミートパイみたいだね
it looks like a hot meat pie.
パパッパッパッパッパッパッパイ！
Papa ppappa papa pie!
パイ？！
Pie?!
アイ！パイ！アイ！いっぱい！でほれほれよ
Ai! Pie! Ai! Full of it, fall in love!
騒げいた少年甘酸っぱいレモン 求人人類パイ満杯大乾杯！
Melted boy, bittersweet lemon, craving humanity, pie-filled grand toast!
完全にほれほれよ
Completely fall in love!
パパッパッパッパッパッパッパイ！パイ？！
Papa ppappa papa pie! Pie?!
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
今日はボロレル
Today is a bolero.
騒げいた少年 甘酸っぱいレモン 求人人類パイ満杯 オープントースターは漏れ漏れよ
Melted boy, bittersweet lemon, craving humanity, full of pies, the toaster is leaking, leaking!
おかわりはアンコール次第ね
Seconds depend on the encore.
終わらないラブコール・ノ・ダンス・デ
In an endless love call dance,
ミルフィーユみたいねあいほろり 頭の中パッパッパッパッパッパア
like mille-feuille, ah, a bit tearful, inside the head, pappappappappaa.
艶やかな脳内の脳裏のジョンレノンもアイパイキュ イマジン ホールザピーポーの祭典
Gorgeous mind, even John Lennon in the back of the mind is ipai-ka, imagine, hall of the people's festival.
ダンスホール 暇人もヒーロー
Dancehall, idlers are also heroes.
乾杯ね今日はボロレル
Cheers today is a bolero.
まじわって人類 馬鹿になって笑って
Intertwining humanity, acting foolish and laughing.
おかわり欲しいでしょ？
Do you want seconds?
全人類構成 部会闘争会の目指すべき一日目は レンジでチンしてパイになるような脳ミソとろとろのよの
All humanity's composition... the day to aim for is like being microwaved into a pie with melting brains.
実現はソロオガにオールナイト
Realization is solo-ga all night,
踊りまして煩悩は相対
dancing so worldly desires are relative.
付きまして成人は増産
Following that, adults are mass-produced.
パパッパッパッパッパッパッパイ！
Papa ppappa papa pie!
人類最高のダンスタイム
Humanity's best dance time!
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
僕らが生まれて初めて知る音は心臓のコードだろ
The first sound we know when we are born is the chord of the heartbeat.
とんとんとんとんとんとんとんとんとん
Ton ton ton ton ton ton ton ton ton!
それはリズムと知った
We knew that was rhythm.
いにしえも今どきもパイbeatが僕たちを包んで繋いでんだろ？
Ancient times and today, isn't pie beat wrapping and connecting us?
パパッパッパッパッパッパッパイ！パイ？！
Papa ppappa papa pie! Pie?!
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
今日はボロレル
Today is a bolero.
騒げいた少年 甘酸っぱいレモン
Melted boy, bittersweet lemon,
求人人類パイ満杯 オープントースターは漏れ漏れよ
craving humanity, full of pies, the toaster is leaking, leaking!
おかわりはアンコール次第ね
Seconds depend on the encore.
終わらないラブコール・ノ・ダンス・デ
In an endless love call dance,
ミルフィーユみたいねあいほろり 頭の中パッパッパッパッパッパア
like mille-feuille, ah, a bit tearful, inside the head, pappappappappaa.
ラララララララララララララ
Lalalalalalalalalala...
まるでバジンロードで踊ってるみたい 生まれ変わったような気分でして
It's like dancing on a virgin road, feeling like I've been reborn.
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
今日はボロレル
Today is a bolero.
まじわって人類 馬鹿になって笑って
Intertwining humanity, acting foolish and laughing.
てててててててて
Te te te te te te te te!
寂ような終わりは近づくけれどさ 終わらないパイのように続きゃいい
The lonely ending approaches, but it'd be nice if it continues like an endless pie.
計算なんてできないが…
I can't calculate, but...
あいっぱい！
Aipai!
パイのようにつづけりゃいい
If it continues like a pie,
計算なんてできないが…
I can't calculate, but...
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
今日はボロレル
Today is a bolero.
騒げいた少年 甘酸っぱいレモン
Melted boy, bittersweet lemon,
求人人類パイ満杯の今日はおっぱいマンパイダー
craving humanity, pie-filled grand toast!
乾杯完全にほれほれよ めくるめく日々に来てね
Completely fall in love, come to the dizzying days!
あなたならいつでもいいよ おかわり欲しいでしょ？
Anytime is fine for you, do you want seconds?
愛包ダンスホール
Aipai Dancehall!
Yeah! Yeah!
パイパイパイパイパイパイパイ！
Pie pie pie pie pie pie pie!
ということで始まりました！ かなけし３Dライブです！
And so it has begun! Kanakeshi 3D Live!
始まったー！いえーい！
It started! Yay!
はい、ということでまずは自己紹介をね、させていただきます！
Yes, so first let us introduce ourselves!
はい！
Yes!
それでは、あずちゃんから！はい！ 右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲットー！
Well then, starting from Azu-chan! Yes! Right hand has a mic, left hand has a map, zero-getting your heart!
ですたー！あずき
That's me! Azuki!
でーす！ 叶建社員です
It's... I'm a Kaneken employee!
あと秘書でーす！
And the secretary!
あれ、いつから秘書になったんだろ？
Wait, when did I become the secretary?
いろいろあるの！いろいろ。ありがとうございます！
There's a lot going on! A lot. Thank you very much!
はい、とてもいい女ということで、
Right, she's a very fine woman,
それでは次は、坂本！
so next is... Sakamoto!
はい！バックバックバックナンバーのま！秘密厳守シークレットな掃除屋さん！ターシャの坂本タクライド！叶建副社長でーす！
Yes! Back-back-Backnumber's-ma! Secret cleaning agent under strict confidentiality! Sakamoto Takride of Tasha! I'm Kaneken's vice president!
え、いつ副社長だっケ？ いつまに副社長になってたんだろ？偶然二番目に入れたんだか…
Huh, when did I become vice president? Somehow I became vice president! By chance I got in second...
秘書長なの、お願いします！
I'm the chief secretary, please!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はい、それでは次は、えーキャッチコピーは悪力50kg！ギュッギュッ握り潰すぞ！ホロライブ4期生天音かなたでーす！かなた社長しております！
Right, so next is, um, my catchphrase is 50kg grip strength! Crushing you to bits! I'm Amane Kanata from Hololive 4th Generation! I serve as President Kanata!
社長！一番偉いです！
President! You're the greatest!
そう、一番偉いはず！はずじゃない、一番偉い！偉いです！
Yes, you should be the greatest! Not should be, you're the greatest! You're great!
そんな感じで盛りだくさんの3Dライブ！ぜひみんなにも楽しんでほしいと思いまーす！
With that kind of vibe, it's a jam-packed 3D live! We hope everyone enjoys it!
さあ、ガンガン盛り上がっていきましょう！行きましょう！
Now, let's get super hyped and go! Let's go!
ということで最後の曲は、ハビッター！
So the final song is, Habit!
君たちったら何でもかんでも分類、区別、ジャンル分けしたがる
All you guys wanna do is label, discriminate, divide
ヒトはなぜか分類したがる習性があるとかないとか
For some reason, humans have this habit to categorize
この世の中2種類の人間がいるとか言う君たちが標的
There's only two types of people in this world, so you say
持ってるヤツと持ってないヤツとか、ちゃんとやるヤツとやってないヤツとか
Those who have it and those who don't, those who do it properly and those who don't
陰キャ陽キャ？キミらは分類しないとどうにも落ち着かない
Introverts or extroverts? You guys can't settle down unless you categorize things
気づかない本ノウの外側を覗いていかない？気が乗らない？
What about the instincts you don't notice? Why not peek outside?
つまりそれはそんなシンプルじゃないもっと曖昧で繊細で不鮮明な何か
In other words, it's not that simple, more ambiguous, delicate, and unclear
例えば持っているのに出せないヤツ、やっているのにいけないヤツ
For example, those who have it but can't show it, those who do it but can't make it work
持っているのに悟ったふりして、スカしてるうちに不安になっちゃったりするヤツ
Those who have it but pretend to be enlightened, and end up feeling anxious
「所詮アンタはギフテッド、アタシは普通の主婦です」ってそれはいいでしょ素晴らしいんでしょう
"After all, you're gifted, and I'm just an ordinary housewife." That's fine, isn't it? Wonderful, isn't it?
不可能の証明の完成なんじゃない？夢を持ってなんて言わない
Isn't that the completion of proving the impossible? I'm not saying you should have dreams
そんな無責任にはなりやしないただその習性に食われないで
I won't be that irresponsible. Just don't let that habit consume you
そうなhabit捨てるたび見えてくるキミの価値
Every time you let go of that habit, your true value becomes clear
オレたちだって動物、こういうのって好物
We're animals too, this kind of thing is our favorite
ここまで言われたらどう？腹の底からこう沸々とお
What do you think now that I've said all this? Normally, you'd feel this bubbling up
オレたちだって動物、故に持ちうべきoriginalな習性、自分自身を分類するなよ
We're animals too, therefore we have our original habits, don't classify yourself
壊して見せろよbad habit
Break that bad habit
オレたちだって動物、こういうのって好物
We're animals too, this kind of thing is our favorite
ここまで言われたらどう？腹の底からこう沸々とお
What do you think now that I've said all this? Normally, you'd feel this bubbling up
オレたちだって動物、故に持ちうべきoriginalな習性、自分自身を分類するなよ
We're animals too, therefore we have our original habits, don't classify yourself
壊して見せろよbad habit
Break that bad habit
オトナのオレが言っちゃいけないこと言っちゃうけど説教するってぶっちゃけ快楽
I'm an adult, so I shouldn't say this, but preaching is actually a pleasure
酒の肴にすりゃもう傑作、でモッテキミも進むキッカイにナリヤ
A masterpiece over drinks, and if it becomes your catalyst to move forward
そりゃそれでwin-winじゃん？
Then it's a win-win, right?
こりゃこれで残念じゃん？そもそもそれってキミ次第だし
This is a pity? It's up to you anyway,
その後なんかオレ興味ないわけ
And I don't care what happens after that
この先キミはどうしたい？って人に問われること自体終わりじゃないと信じたいけど
What do you want to do from here on out? Being asked that, I want to believe it's not the end
そうじゃなきゃかなりの非常事態
But if not, it's a major crisis
キミたちがその分類された普通の箱でくすぶってるからさオレは人生イージーモード
Because you're stuck in those categorized ordinary boxes, I'm living an easy life
ずっとそこで眠っててアラサーオレはそもそもスペックが低い
Just sleeping there in my thirties, I'm just not that capable
だから足掻いて藻掻いて見苦しく吠えてオレのあの頃を分類したら
So I struggled and screamed ugly, if you categorize my past
誰の目から見ても明かすぐ世の中金だとか愛だとか
It's obvious to anyone, why do you reduce the world to money, love
運だとか縁だとかなぜ二文字で片付けいちゃうの
Luck, or fate, in two syllables?
オレたちはもっと曖昧で複雑で不鮮明な何か
We're more ambiguous, complex, and unclear
悟ったふりして奢るなよキミにキミを分類する能力なんてない
Don't pretend to be enlightened and arrogant, you don't have the ability to categorize yourself
オレたちだって動物、こういうのって好物
We're animals too, this kind of thing is our favorite
ここまで言われたらどう？腹の底からこう沸々とお
What do you think now that I've said all this? Normally, you'd feel this bubbling up
なんてな
Or so I say
オレたちだって動物、こういうのって好物
We're animals too, this kind of thing is our favorite
ここまで言われたらどう？腹の底からこう沸々とお
What do you think now that I've said all this? Normally, you'd feel this bubbling up
オレたちだって動物、故に持ちうべきoriginalな習性、自分自身を分類するなよ
We're animals too, therefore we have our original habits, don't classify yourself
壊して見せろよbad habit
Break that bad habit
君たちだって動物 こういうのって好物
You guys are animals too, this is your favorite.
ここまで言われたらどう？ 普通腹の底からこう沸々と
What do you think now that you've been told this? Normally, it boils up deep inside.
そう俺たちだって動物 故に持ちうるオリジナルな習性
Yes, we're animals too, hence our own original habits.
自分自身を分類するなよ 壊してみせろよそのbad habit
Don't classify yourself, break that bad habit.
壊してみせろよそのbad habit
Break that bad habit.
貴方は風のように
Like the wind,
目を閉じては夕暮れ
you close your eyes in the twilight,
何を考えているんだろうか
I wonder what you're thinking about.
目蓋を開いていた
With your eyelids open...
貴方の目はビードロ
Your eyes are like glass,
少しだけ晴るの匂いがした
with a faint scent of clearing.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom for the sake of clearing!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you, the clearing.
胸を打つ音よ響け 僕ら晴る風
Echo out, sound striking the heart, we are the clearing wind.
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Go beyond those clouds, far, still far away.
貴方は晴れ模様に 目を閉じては青色
You, in fair weather, close your eyes to the blue.
何が悲しいのだろうか
What is making you sad?
目蓋を開いている
With your eyelids open,
貴方の目にビードロ 今少し雨の匂いがした
your eyes are like glass, now with a faint scent of rain.
泣きに泣き、空よ泣け 泣いて雨のせい
Cry, oh sky, and weep, weep because of the rain.
降り頻る雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even in the frequent rain, above the clouds, it's clearing.
土を打つ音よ響け 僕ら春荒れ
Resonate, sound hitting the ground, we are the stormy spring.
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Crossing over that sea, far, still far away.
通り雨 草を戦がせ
A passing shower, swaying the grass,
羊雲 あれも春のせい
cumulus clouds, also because of spring.
風のように 胸に春乗せ 晴るを待つ
Like the wind, carrying spring on our chests, waiting for clearing.
晴れに晴れ、空よ裂け 裂いて春のせい
Clear up, oh sky, and tear open for the sake of spring!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you, the clearing.
胸を打つ音奏で 僕ら春風
Playing the sound that strikes the heart, we are the spring breeze.
音に聴く晴るの風 さあこの歌よ響け
Listen to the sound of the clearing wind, now let this song echo!
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom for the sake of clearing!
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Go beyond those clouds, far, still far away.
通り雨 草をそよがせ
A passing shower, swaying the grass,
羊雲 あれも春のせい
cumulus clouds, also because of spring.
風のように 胸に春乗せ 春を待つ
Like the wind, carrying spring on our chests, waiting for spring.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom for the sake of clearing!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you, the clearing.
降り止まぬ雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even the ceaseless rain, above the clouds, it's clearing.
あなたを飾る晴る 胸を打つ音轟かせて
Adorning you, the clearing, echoing the sound striking the heart.
僕ら春風 音に聴く晴るの風
We are the spring breeze, listening to the sound of the clearing wind.
さあこの歌よ投げ
Now, cast this song out!
踊りに聴く春の風 さあこの歌よ投げ
Dancing to the clearing wind, now cast this song out!
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom for the sake of clearing!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you, the clearing.
あの雲も超えてゆき
Surpassing those clouds,
遠く まだ遠くまで
farther, still farther away...
つまらないデイイズももう散々ね！
Boring days are already over!
奇跡願っているだけの人生
A life where you're just wishing for miracles
Watch me do...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without any tricks or secrets
I wanna be free!
だってまだふたしだし
Because I'm still at the start,
お召しな馬車 飛び乗ってDriving
Jump on the carriage and start drivin'
あたすは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great makeover!
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔物のように
The second hand ticks loudly like a monster urging the night,
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法 それならば駆け抜けて思い通り！
Life is magic that melts in an instant—if so, run through it as you wish!
我儘のままに 爛れに注意
Following selfishness, beware of decay,
洒落た街でDancing
dancing in a stylish city.
左様ならグッバイ劣等感
Say goodbye to inferiority complex,
何時かは喝采クラップオデエンス
someday, applause and cheers from the audience.
皆々御唱和あれ！
Everyone, join in and sing along!
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
こんがらっがても仕樣が無い
Even if it gets tangled, it can't be helped,
ガラスシューズで踊るTonight
dancing in glass shoes tonight.
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
今夜に明日など無い ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
There's no tomorrow tonight, so those who dance freely win, right?
Dance！ラララリホ
Dance! La la la li ho
どんな問題も解法は一つ
Every problem has only one solution,
白紙も正解も間違いも愛す
loving blank papers, correct answers, and mistakes.
本当のあたしの理想
My true ideal—
なんだか世界は限界の気がして
the world somehow feels like it's at its limit,
ただただ安心じゃあ心配
and just being safe is worrying.
今すぐjumpin', jumpin' out
Jumpin' out right now,
chitty-chitty, bang-bang
chitty, bang-bang
意気地なく愚図に危機感抱く日々に
In days when I cowardice-driven feel an urgent crisis,
ギリギリ爆発寸前
explosive feelings are at the absolute limit—
たった今発散してしまおうか
should I just let it all out right now?
まだまだびびっで壇上に乱射
Still firing away nervously on stage,
一発じゃあ打ち足りないわ
one shot is not nearly enough.
ついに導き出した君にアンサー
Finally, I found the answer for you,
ハイになるまで踊っていようよ
dancing until we get high.
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
お召しな馬車 飛び乗ってDriving
Jump on the carriage and start drivin'
あたすは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great makeover!
我儘のままに 爛れに注意
Following selfishness, beware of decay,
洒落た街でDancing
dancing in a stylish city.
左様ならグッバイ劣等感
Say goodbye to inferiority complex,
何時かは喝采クラップオデエンス
someday, applause and cheers from the audience.
皆々御唱和あれ！
Everyone, join in and sing along!
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
こんがらっがても仕樣が無い
Even if it gets tangled, it can't be helped,
ガラスシューズで踊るTonight
dancing in glass shoes tonight.
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
今夜に明日など無い
There's no tomorrow tonight,
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
so those who dance freely win, right?
こんがらっがても仕樣が無い
Even if it gets tangled, it can't be helped,
ガラスシューズで踊るTonight
dancing in glass shoes tonight.
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
今夜に明日など無い
There's no tomorrow tonight,
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
so those who dance freely win, right?
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa)
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
こんがらっがても仕樣が無い ガラスシューズで踊るTonight
Even if it gets tangled, dancing in glass shoes tonight,
（BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA） （BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA, YEAH）
(Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah)
今夜に明日など無い
There's no tomorrow tonight,
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
so those who dance freely win, right?
旅のはじまりは もう思い出せない
I can't recall the beginning of my journey anymore
気づいたら ここにいた
When I noticed it, I was here
季節が破けて 未発見赤外線
The seasons tear apart and undiscovered infrared rays
感じる目が 迷子になる
make my sensing eyes get lost
たぶん失うのだ
I will probably lose
命がけの想い
my desperate thoughts
戦うように恋した
I fell in love as if it were war
ひたすらに夢を掘った
I earnestly dug up my dreams
その星に降りたかった
I wanted to land on that star
君の空飛びたかった
I wanted to fly through your sky
誰か空虚の輪郭をそっと撫でてくれないか
Won't someone softly stroke the outline of the void?
胸の鼓動にけとばされて転がり出た愛のことば
Kicked away by the pounding of my chest, words of love tumbled out
だけど困ったな応答がない
But isn't it troubling? There's no response
宿命にはりつけられた北極星が燃えている
Crucified by fate, the North Star is burning
君をかきむしって濁らせた
I scratched you out and made you a cloudy blur
なのに可憐に笑うとこ好きだったよ
Yet I loved how you smiled so sweetly
君がいないなら意味なんてなくなるから 人は全部消えればいい
Because if you're gone, there's no meaning—all people should just disappear
愛がなくなれば心だっていらないから この世界も消えてしまえ
If there's no love, I don't even need a heart, so this world can vanish too
ずっとなんとかだった
It was always painful...
命がけの出会い
Our desperate meeting
もがくように夢見た
I dreamed as if struggling
やみくもに手を伸ばした
I reached out my hands blindly
その胸に聞きたかった
I wanted to listen to your heart
君と虹架けたかった
I wanted to build a rainbow with you
誰か夜明けの感傷でぎゅっと抱いてくれないか
Won't someone embrace me tightly with the sentiment of dawn?
夢の軌道にはじかれて飛び散るだけの愛のなみだ
Tears of love merely scattering, repelled by the orbit of dreams.
君がいなければ 意味なんてなくなるから
If you aren't here, it loses all meaning,
人は全部 冷えればいい
so everyone might as well just get cold.
愛がなくなれば 心だって要らないから
If love disappears, I won't need a heart,
この世界も 消してしまえ
so erase this world too.
ずっと苦しかった 命がけの出会い
It was always painful, a life-or-death encounter.
もがくように夢見た 闇雲に手を伸ばした
I dreamed as if struggling, reaching out blindly.
そのままで気付きたかった
I wanted to realize it just like that,
君とに出会いたかった
I wanted to meet you.
誰か夜明けの干渉で
Won't someone, with the emotion of dawn,
ぎゅっと抱いてくれないか
hold me tight?
夢の軌道に弾かれて 飛び散るだけの愛の涙
Tears of love scattering, repelled by the orbit of dreams.
それが巻き起こす 痛みでもいい
Even if it's the pain that brings,
宿命に呼び戻された
I was called back to destiny.
北極星が泣いてる この狭い路地を抜け出すなら
The North Star is crying. If we slip out of this alley,
君をずっと愛した 死にたいよ
I loved you all along, I want to die.
捨てられるような 命がけの終わり
A life-or-death end like being thrown away.
戦うように愛した 無茶苦茶に夢を蹴った
I loved as if fighting, kicked my dreams recklessly.
その星に果てたかった
I wanted to end on that star,
君のその先たかった
I wanted to go beyond you...
誰か来る今日の輪郭を
Won't someone gently caress
そっと撫でてくれないか
today's approaching outline?
時のあの日に鍵がかけられて 救えなかった愛の言葉
Words of love locked away on that day, un-saved.
だからもう一度 答えが欲しい 宿命に張り付けられた
That's why I want an answer once more, nailed to destiny.
北極星が燃えてる 君を抱きしめて見殺せた
The North Star is burning. I hugged you and let you die,
なのに華麗に笑うどこ
yet you smile brilliantly... where?
君を抱きしめて見殺せた なのに華麗に笑うどこ
I hugged you and let you die, yet you smile brilliantly...
好きだったよ
I loved you.
世界で一番おひめさま
I'm the number one princess
そう言う扱い心得てよね
in the whole wide world, so know how to treat me.
ワールドイズマイン
[Title: World is Mine]
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気付くこと
Number one: Notice when my hair is styled differently.
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね?
Number two: Look closely all the way to my shoes, okay?
その三 わたしの一言には 三つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Answer every word with three words.
わかったら 右手がお留守なのをなんとかして!
If you get it, fix my empty right hand!
別にわがままなんて 言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
キミに心から思って欲しいの「かわいい」って
I just want you to truly think I'm cute.
世界で一番おひめさま
I'm the number one princess
気が付いて ねえねえ
in the world. Notice me, hey hey.
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is out of the question!
わたしを誰だと思ってるの?
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか あまいものが食べたい!
I want something sweet right now!
いますぐに よね?
Right now, okay?
欠点? かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You mean adorable mistakes.
文句は許しませんの
Complaints are not allowed!
あのね? 私の話ちゃんと聞いてる? ちょっと...
Hey, are you listening to my story? Wait...
あっ、それとね? 白いおうさまさん 決まっているでしょ? 迎えに来て
Oh, and a white prince, you've decided on that, right? Come pick me up.
分かったなら かしずいて 手を取って “おひめさま”って
If you understand, kneel and take my hand, say "my princess."
別に わがままなんて 言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
でもね 少しっくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ?
But you know, it's okay if you scold me a little!
世界でわたしだけのおうさまさん
A prince who is only mine in this world,
気が付いて ほらほら おててが空いています
notice me, hey hey, both my hands are empty!
無口で無愛想なおうさまさん
A prince who is so silent and cold,
もう どうして!
oh why!
気が付いてよ早く ねえ!
Hurry up and notice, hey!
たくさんいじごの乗ったショートケーキ
A shortcake topped with lots of strawberries,
こだわりたまごのとろける潤沢プリン!
a melting rich pudding with special eggs!
みんな みんな あきらめます
Everyone, everyone gives up.
わがままな子だと思わないで お願い
Please don't think I'm a selfish girl,
わたしだって本気出せばできるもん
I can do it if I really try.
あとで後悔するわよ 当然です!
You'll regret it later. Of course!
世界で一番おひめさま
The world's number one princess,
そういう扱い心得てよね
So make sure you know how to treat me.
その一 いつもと違う
First, notice when my hair
髪型に気付くこと
is styled differently than usual.
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね?
Second, look all the way down at my shoes, okay?
その三 わたしの一言には
Third, answer my every word
三つの言葉で返事すること
with a three-word response.
わかったら 右手がお留守番なのを
If you understand, do something
なんとかして!
about my lonely right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
キミに心から思ってほしいの
I just want you to truly feel from the heart
かわいいって
that I'm cute.
世界で一番おひめさま
The world's number one princess,
気付いて ねぇねぇ
Notice me, hey, hey.
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is out of the question.
わたしを誰だと思ってるの?
Who do you think I am?
もう何だか 甘いものが食べたい!
Right now, I want something sweet to eat!
いますぐよ 聞いてる?
Right now! Are you listening?
あ、それとね?白いおうさま
Oh, and also, my white king,
決まってるでしょ?
that's a given, right?
迎えに来て
Come and welcome me.
わかったらかしずいてて
If you understand, kneel down,
手を取って
take my hand,
おひめさまって
and call me your princess.
別に わがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
でもね 少しくらい小突いてくれたっていいのよ
though it's okay to tease me just a little.
世界でわたしたけのおうさま
My one and only king in the world,
気付いて ほらほら
Notice me, come on, come on,
おててが空いています
My hands are empty.
無口で無愛想なおうさま
My silent and aloof king,
声に出して言ってよ!
Say it out loud!
早く気付いてよ
Hurry up and notice!
ねぇ!
Hey!
ぜったい キミは
You definitely
ぜんぜん わかってない!
don't understand at all!
何も わかってないわ
You don't understand anything.
たくさんのいちごの載ったショートケーキ
A shortcake topped with loads of strawberries,
こだわりたまごのとろける潤沢プリン!
Rich pudding melting with carefully selected eggs!
みんな みんな あきらめます
I'll give up all of them,
わがままだと思わないで お願い
Please don't think I'm being selfish.
わたしだって本気出せばできるもんだ
I can do it if I really try,
あとで後悔 するわよ
You'll regret it later.
当然です!だってわたしは
Naturally! Because I am
世界で一番おひめさま
The world's number one princess.
ちゃんと見ていてね
Keep your eyes properly on me,
どこかに行っちゃうよ?
Or I'll go somewhere else!
後ろから抱きしめられた…
You hugged me from behind...
しかも いきなり ちょっと!
And so suddenly, hey!
「危ないよ 轢かれるところだった」
"Watch out, you almost got run over,"
そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
You said, looking away.
…キミのほうが危ないわよ
...You're the dangerous one here.
Ah!
Hey, baby!
はい、ということで、お聴きいただいたのは、
Right, so, what you just listened to were
ハビット、春、ビビデバ、ノウザンクロス、ワールドイズマインでした！
HABIT, Haru, Bibideba, Northern Cross, and World is Mine!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you very much!
ここからも、ここ、ここ、ここからも、ここから、ここからもね！
From here on too, from right here, right here!
怒涛の神ケンスパを見せていくので、最後までついてきてください！
We'll keep showing an onslaught of amazing performances, so please stay with us to the end!
イエーイ！
Yay!
それでは、次はあずき先輩のオリジナル楽曲「Intersection」をお楽しみいただきます！どうぞ！
Now, next up is AZKi-senpai's original song, "Intersection"! Here we go!
気にしないでなんて言わないで
Don't say "don't worry about it"
ホントはいつも正直じゃないけど
The truth is I'm never honest,
気がついてよなんて言えなくて
And I can't even say "notice me".
嘘ばかり
Just lies...
(can’t stop love with you)
(Can't stop love with you)
溺れたいな i gotcha ぎゅっと
I want to fall in love, i gotcha, tightly
ハマる君の交差点
The intersection where you and I get caught up
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと
I want to change, I want more of that feeling
yellow ちょいアブないね (ah)
Yellow, a little bit dangerous (ah)
Knock it out!
突き抜けろ 熱情を 先駆け奪い去ってよ
Ring out your passion, and rush to steal it away!
Knock it out, knocking it out, Hey! Hey!
それフェイク (笑) はい、にゃにゃにゃ
That's fake (lol) Yes, nya nya nya
無敵な 愛愛愛愛 会いたいな
Invincible, love love love love, I want to see you
着飾れ ほらピース 散らばり狂い咲かない
Dress up, come on peace, scattered and blooming madly
ガシンショウガン 燃やせプライド
Smash it through, burn your pride!
擬態ごっこ いいねもっと
Imitation game, give me more
すまんないアスファルト越しのシンデレラ
Sorry, Cinderella across the asphalt
叶えたい 消えたい 歪んでいくんだ
I want to make it come true, I want to vanish, I'm distorting
僕と僕との境界線
The boundary line between me and myself
どれも正解で どれも世界だ
Every answer is correct, every world is real
叶えたい 消えたい 歪んでいくんだ
I want to make it come true, I want to vanish, I'm distorting
ずっと僕との境界線
Always the boundary line between me and myself
モードクドクドク... さよならはいもうわかんない 興味がないなら
Modoku doku doku... Goodbye, I don't get it anymore, if you have no interest
ドク ドク ドク... 果たせない 私のタイム 奪って置いて
Doku doku doku... Stole my time that could never be fulfilled
無駄 結論 非効率ダネ
Useless, in conclusion, highly inefficient
限界 もうもっと 果たしてちょうだい 面倒ねあなたの指示
Limit, give me even more, fulfill it already, your instructions are such a hassle
面倒ね アゴでしか使えないお前は
What a pain. You're someone I can only order around.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it!
ブルッちゃダメなのよカモレモノね
You mustn't tremble, you're easy prey, right?
モードクドク 至って冷静
Highly poisonous mode, staying completely calm.
表情も変えないでナンパ
Approaching without even changing my expression.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it!
笑っちゃダメなの？綺麗なよろですね
Can't I laugh? What a lovely night, isn't it?
素敵なドックアドクなミュージック
A wonderful, poisonous, dark music.
荒々しく向けたその牙になれ
Become the fangs bared so fiercely,
極端な善になるまで愛しあえるね
Until we become absolute goodness, we can love each other, right?
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
貪欲で満たして ブクブクに恋でこやして
Fill yourself with greed, fattening up with bubbling love.
お気楽ちょっかい 笑っちゃうくらい
Carefree teasing, enough to make you laugh,
たんと愛愛愛愛 love you
Lots of love, love, love, love you!
ボクが一番カワイイにゃん！
I'm the cutest cat!
にゃんにゃん 君とずっとずっとたいので
Meow meow, wanting to stay with you forever,
ボクに首輪をしといてね？
Put a collar on me, okay?
分かってないね そんなのなくたって
You don't get it, even without something like that,
ボクは君の運命のにゃん！にゃん！
I'm your destined kitty, meow, meow!
夢が覚めてしまうまで 鈴の鳴るたび怯えてね？
Until the dream fades, keep trembling every time the bell rings, okay?
君の愛のぜんぶをください
Give me all of your love,
そしたら絶対絶対 にゃんにゃんなのだ！
Then I'll definitely, definitely be your kitty!
なんとかまって にゃんにゃん！
Somehow wait, meow meow!
前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Advance is top priority! Welcome me properly,
わんだらだら！
Wanderer-da-da!
空想創造 ちゃんと共感して
Fantasy creation, empathize properly,
わんだらだら！
Wanderer-da-da!
楽しいことも
Even enjoyable things,
努力とは最後まで諦めないこと
Effort means never giving up until the very end,
メモっておいて！
Make a note of it!
最後まで私のこと覚えてくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの 分かってよ わかってよね
I feel like I'm about to disappear, please understand, won't you?
本当のところどうなの？いずれは卒業するんでしょう？
What's the truth of it all? Eventually, you'll graduate, right?
日常に戻ったら私はいなくなるの
Once we return to everyday life, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見てるよ またねばいばい
I'm dreaming a dream like life. See you later, bye-bye.
あたしジャンク不脳なし思考回路
I'm a junk, brainless, useless thought circuit,
鳴らす大破的な異常行動
Sounding off catastrophic, abnormal behavior.
もっとしたい もっとしたい 回りたい 踏まれたいなら
If you want to do more, spin more, or be stepped on,
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol!
人生リセットの断崖絶壁
The precipice of resetting life,
品性に欠っとドジラ気味
Lacking in grace and somewhat clumsy.
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol!
人生リセットボタンぽち
「これは、3人の社員による、果てなき労働の物語である」
"This is a story of endless labor by three employees."
社員番号 No.3 超大型新人 AZKi
Employee ID No.3, super rookie AZKi!
先輩だけどマジ後輩 天然キャラなんて誤解誤解
Senior yet seriously a junior, thinking she's a natural airhead is a total misunderstanding!
いけいけGO!GO! 詰まったら即セーブ&ロード
Go go, let's go! If you get stuck, immediately save & load!
今日も現場へ急行 でもそろそろ払ってね給料！
Rushing to the site today too, but pay us our salary soon!
社員番号 No.2 スーパー秘書 沙花叉！
Employee ID No.2, super secretary Sakamata!
大きなお口でパクパク 何だって食べちゃうがぶっくー！
Munching away with a big mouth, gobbling up anything, gapuku!
特徴は生意気スキル お風呂キャンセル 特級スメル
Her traits are cheeky skills, skipping baths, and a top-tier smell!
もう実質副社長 気を抜いたらやっちゃう下剋上
Practically the vice president already, if you let your guard down she'll pull off an overthrow!
社員番号 No.1 社長 だよ かなた！
Employee ID No.1, president Kanata!
美人でキュートで声が最高で 笑顔で清楚でボクっ子天使で オシャレでセクシー スタイル抜群
Beautiful, cute, with an amazing voice, smiling, pure, bo-boyish angel, stylish, sexy, and with a fabulous figure!
愛情たっぷりボンキュッボン とにかく凄いぞ かなた社長！
Overflowing with love, bong-qu-bon, anyway she's amazing, President Kanata!
最強無敵三人で
As an invincible trio,
明るい未来 作りましょう
Let's build a bright future!
やり甲斐だらけ それゆけ
Full of fulfillment, off we go!
誇り高き オシゴトロード
The proud work road!
推せ推せよ 声出せよ
Support us, raise your voices!
ラブを心に抱け 今見せよ
Hold love in your hearts, show it now!
光らせよ ロマンスを捧げて
Make it shine, dedicate your romance!
ハチャメチャで スチャラカで
Wild and carefree,
めちゃくちゃ頑張って生きりゃんせ
Work like crazy and live life to the fullest!
ルール違反したら 握り潰しちゃうぞ
If you violate the rules, we'll crush you to pieces!
ギュッギュッ ギュッギュッ ギュッ
Squeezing tight, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze!
「全世界の推し事中のみなさん、こんにちは、こんばんは、おはようございまーす！」
"Hello, good evening, good morning to everyone currently at work!"
今日もみんな元気にもりもり、働いてえらい！
Working hard and full of energy today, you're amazing!
推しの幸せは？
What is an oshi's happiness?
そう、自分の幸せ！
That's right, one's own happiness!
ってわけで、働け諸君！
So with that said, get to work, everyone!
サーイェッサー！
Sir, yes, sir!
どっこいしょ！どっこいしょ！
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
エビバディ労働GO!
Everybody, work GO!
ファイトだえいいおー！
Fight, oh-oh-oh!
脳天カチ割る声をだせ～！
Let out a voice that splits your skull open!
開拓者！これが限界アリーナツアー
Pioneers! This is the limit arena tour!
沙花叉！飼育員！ぶち上げDJ B2B
Sakamata! Keepers! Hype DJ B2B!
かなた！へい民！全員見てんぞ永遠に
Kanata! Heimin! Watch us forever!
天界等級オシゴトロード WORKING! WORKING! WAR!
Heavenly-rank Work Road, WORKING! WORKING! WAR!
推せ推せよ (Yeah!)
Support us, support us! (Yeah!)
声出せよ (Hey!)
Raise your voices! (Hey!)
なんたってアイドルだからね
Because we're idols, after all!
沼ハマって (Yeah!)
Fall deep in the swamp! (Yeah!)
床になって (Hey!)
Become the floor! (Hey!)
ロマンスを捧げて
Dedicate your romance!
夢みたいな 世界みたいな
Like a dream, like a world...
みんな一緒に叶えよ
Let's make it come true together!
ルール違反したら 握り潰しちゃうぞ
Break the rules and I'll crush you!
ギュッギュッギュッギュッ
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze...
WORKING... WORKING...
はい、皆さん！
Everyone!
や、できましたねー！
Man, we finally did it!
ついに、かなけんのオリジナル楽曲ができました！
Finally, Kanaken's original song is completed!
よっしゃー！よっしゃー！しゃかしゃかしゃか！
Let's go! Shaka shaka shaka!
はい、もうね、本当待望だよね。
Yeah, I mean, we've really been waiting for this.
そうだよ。作りたいて言ってから...
That's right. Ever since we said we wanted to make it...
作りたいて言ってやっと形になって。やっとだよ！
Saying we wanted to make it and finally seeing it take shape. Finally!
みんな盛り上がってくれてましたら、ありがとね！
Thank you everyone for getting so hyped up!
どうだったかな？めちゃくちゃね、労働してますね。
How was it? We're really working hard, huh?
そうでしょ、本当に。やっちゃってますね。ブラックですよ、だいぶ。
Exactly. We really went for it. It's pretty black-company style.
え、大丈夫か？このブラックだったんだ。
Wait, is this okay? It was this black?
この時代、ブラックまずいっすか？いやいやいやいや
Is being black company bad in this day and age? No, no, no, no...
デタラメすよね。ですよね。ですよね。
It's nonsense, right? Totally. Totally.
給料は、ほら、払いまくってますよ。そ、そう、そうだっけ？
We're paying out salaries like crazy, you know. R-Right, is that right?
給料？はい、という...
Salary? Yeah, so...
いやだって出たオリジナル曲、こちらのオリジナル曲なんでございますけれども
But anyway, this new original song is our unit's original song, but...
なんとなんとなんと、MVが、はい、作られておりますよ！
Believe it or not, an MV has been created, yes!
このあと22時から、AZKiチャンネルで公開されまーす！
It will be released tonight at 10 PM on AZKi's channel!
イェーイ！お願いします！お願いしまーす！
Yay! Please check it out! Please do!
そしてそして、そのあとデジタル配信が、なんとこのあと24時から、開始しまーす！
And furthermore, digital distribution will start at midnight tonight!
イェーイ！いっぱいい聞いてね！聞いてください！
Yay! Please listen to it a lot! Please listen!
ということで、本当に念願の、マジでね、もう年単位でさ。
So, this has truly been our long-cherished wish, literally taking years.
ね、企画書書いたりとかさ、本当にいっぱいしゃべって準備してきまして。
Right, writing proposal documents and talking a lot to prepare.
けれどさ、ね、3Dライブ念願叶えられましたね！叶いましたね！やったね！この日が来たね！
But you know, we were finally able to fulfill our dream of a 3D live! We did it! Yay! This day has finally come!
ということで、僕ら2人に手紙を書いてきちゃいました！
And so, I wrote letters to you two!
え？え？聞いてません、社長。
Huh? What? We didn't hear about this, Boss.
え、サプライズで読んでくれるんですか？どういう手紙なんだ？
Oh, are you reading it as a surprise? What kind of letter is it?
まじめなやつをね。まじめなやつって言うな！
A serious one. Don't call it a serious one!
って言いながらじゃなくて。それでは、AZちゃんへ。
Instead of saying that... Now then, to AZ-chan.
かなけんに入ってくれて本当にありがとう。AZちゃんがそせんしてコラボの案を出してくれたり、かなけんでのオリジナル曲MVを進行してくれたり、本当に助かりました。
Thank you so much for joining Kanaken. AZ-chan took the initiative to propose collaborations, and pushed forward with Kanaken's original song MV, which really helped us out.
またAZちゃんへの信頼がどんどんあまりに熱くなりまくりました。
My trust in AZ-chan has grown stronger and hotter than ever.
本当に手伝ってくれてありがとうございます。本当に支えでき...
Thank you so much for helping out. Really supporting...
AZちゃんとかねけんはでの活動のこと考えて交わすLINEはめちゃめちゃ楽しいし、一緒に音楽について話すのも最高の幸せです。
Exchanging texts thinking about activities with AZ-chan and Kanaken is super fun, and talking about music together is the ultimate happiness.
AZちゃんとう出会えて本当によかったです。これからもたくさんしゃべろうね！ありがとう。
I'm so glad I met AZ-chan. Let's keep talking a lot! Thank you.
いつもありがとう。こちらこそありがとう。これからも背中合わせでよろ...
Thank you always. Thank you too. Let's keep supporting each other back-to-back...
ありがとうね、本当。温かくしてくれてありがとう。
Thank you so much, really. Thank you for making it so warm.
はい、ということで、ありがとう。はい。
Yes, so, thank you. Yes.
うん、坂本は？そうだよよね。忘れないでね！坂本の大事だよ！
Yeah, what about Sakamata? That's right. Don't forget! Sakamata is important too!
じゃあ、坂本だね。実はお手紙ありますか？読ませていただきますね。
Ah, Sakamata's turn. Actually, do you have a letter? Let me read it.
かなけんで
With Kanaken...
何かやりたいねという始まりから、3Dライブができるまでに至るなんて、うん、思ってもいませんでした。
From wanting to do something together to actually being able to hold a 3D live, yeah, I never would've imagined it.
そうだね。二人でマイクラをしてた時は想像もしていなかったと思います。
That's right. When we used to play Minecraft together, I never could've imagined this.
うん。常闇は生意気な女ですが、うん？
Yeah. Tokoyami is a sassy girl, but— huh?
とても可愛い後輩で、僕が活動のことで、辛いことがあったとき、うん、あの朝からねチャットして、LINEして、うん。
She's a very cute junior. When I had a hard time with my activities, yeah, we'd chat and line from the morning, yeah.
ってなんかを察して、天羽は、うん、ちょっと話す？
Sensing something was up, Kanata was like, "Wanna talk for a bit?"
って、声かけてくれて、2時間くらい喋ってくれたよね。
She reached out to me and talked with me for about two hours.
いや、だからびっくりしてね。びっくりした、気づかれたんだと思って、本当にありましたよねと、気遣い屋さんのね、ところにいっぱい甘わせてもらいました。
I was really surprised. I thought, "She noticed," and I really leaned on her considerate nature.
えー、常闇はしんどいときとか、寂しいときはね、僕のこの大きな胸に甘えてください。うん。
Um, Tokoyami, when times are tough or you're lonely, please lean on my big chest. Yeah.
ま、
Well...
ないけど、でも、ありますが、
Not really, but... well, there are times...
ないけど、でも本当に甘えてほしいと嬉しいなって思う、そう言ってもらえたのが、このね、かなけんの期間ってね、気づいてきたことだよね。
Not really, but I'm really happy when you say you want me to lean on you. That's something I've realized during this Kanaken period.
泣かないで！泣かないで！こんな私だけどさ、
Don't cry! Don't cry! Even though I'm like this...
卒業まではよろしく。ずっと味方だよ。
Thanks until graduation. I'm always on your side.
泣かないで。ありがとね。ね、お互い味方だよ。ね。
Don't cry. Thank you. We're always on each other's side.
大丈夫の、大丈夫の、大丈夫？大丈夫！
Are you okay? Are you okay? Are you okay? I'm okay!
と、いうことで、うふふ。うわあ、
And with that, hehe. Wow...
実はですね、次で最後の曲に、なりますので、ラストか。ずっと歌わせて頂きたい、思いますね。ということで、はい、
Actually, the next song will be our last, so... the last one. We'd love to keep singing. So, yes...
それでは3人でいきますか。せーの、アワーブライトパレード！
Shall the three of us go? Ready, set, Our Bright Parade!
あれ パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's time to shine!
呼び合う声を 合図に
I hear the voices calling out your name
パレード パレード パレード 探しに行く
Parade, parade, parade! A new journey awaits
スタートは 何度だって
Just hit reset and we can start again
ただ 独り言 綴った
I weave lonely words into echoes
ただ 始まりたくて 走った
I run because I heard a voice say "go!"
遠く 暗がり に 灯った
Far away, lighting up all the darkness
それは 眩し過ぎた 名前
It's a name, shining for us to notice
それは 優し過ぎる 思い出もっと
Memories that fill us up with kindness and love
近づけと 手を伸ばした 思いがけず 結び合った
You reach out and tell me to come close, every one that they called "the lost"
ほら 今 迷子は
Here we are as "us"
“僕等” になった
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's time to shine!
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
When disappointment gets in your way, love will shine
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Feel the wind and wishes, your wings will take you high
ささやかな 祈りは 光 終わりなき 兆し
These silent prayers will become our light, guiding us on an endless flight
君を 見つけたこと 胸を 張れるよ
Finally, we found each other, I can stand tall and say
ここから これから
Starting from here, starting right now
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ 頼りない 予感 を 歌おう
We sing, full of uncertain feelings
恥ずかしかなんて ないよ 誰も 解決ない イマジナリー
We sing, and we're not afraid of what they think, no one can decode what we're imagining
いつか また逢える おまじない
They don't know our magic and our destiny
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
When we met, this was an empty story
数え切れない 言の葉
Too many words to count them all out
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を合図に
Shining bright, taking cues from our calling voices!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 探しに行く スタートは何度だって
Parade, Parade, Parade! No matter how many times we start anew!
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等” になった
Look, now the lost ones have become "us."
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! How beautiful it is!
許し合える 刹那 夜はきらめく
In moments of mutual forgiveness, the night sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド また とない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope—a once-in-a-lifetime sky!
相応しい 旅路とは 君 と在ることさ
A fitting journey is simply being here with you.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき 兆し
Our quiet prayers are a light, an endless omen.
君 を見つけたこと 胸 を張れるよ
I can hold my head high knowing I found you.
ここから これから
From here on, starting now—
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を 歌おう 恥ずかしそう なんてないよ
Let's sing of our uncertain premonition; there's nothing to be shy about.
誰一人解けない イマジネーション
An imagination no one can unravel,
いつか また逢える おまじない
a spell that we will meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that began from zero on that day—
数え切れない 言の葉
countless words,
数え切れる ような 想いじゃないさ
not feelings that can be easily counted.
ほら 今 “僕等”を 一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call "us" as one!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! Shining bright!
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your affection along too!
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings—we can take flight!
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき 兆し
Our quiet prayers are a light, an endless omen.
君 と飛び込んでいく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in with you—what a wonderful start!
ここから これから
From here on, starting now—
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうみんな！ またね！
Thank you everyone! See you again!